<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>NaPi-X Blog</title>
        <link>https://napi-x.com/blog</link>
        <description>NaPi-X Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We are up and running in 2025 season !]]></title>
            <link>https://napi-x.com/blog/2025/01/09/index</link>
            <guid>https://napi-x.com/blog/2025/01/09/index</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Manifest]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="manifest">Manifest<a href="https://napi-x.com/blog/2025/01/09/index#manifest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Manifest" title="Direct link to Manifest">​</a></h2>
<p>We want to present the manifest of Napi-X in first post.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-goal">Our Goal<a href="https://napi-x.com/blog/2025/01/09/index#our-goal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Goal" title="Direct link to Our Goal">​</a></h2>
<p>To create a Linux system for single-board computers, routers, and embedded devices that is optimized, user-friendly, and easy to understand, with a lightweight reactive management interface.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-backstory-of-the-napi-x-project">The Backstory of the Napi-X Project<a href="https://napi-x.com/blog/2025/01/09/index#the-backstory-of-the-napi-x-project" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The Backstory of the Napi-X Project" title="Direct link to The Backstory of the Napi-X Project">​</a></h2>
<p>In 2023 and 2024, we worked extensively on our own Linux distribution (NapiOS) for our embedded devices. However, while working with clients and partners, it became clear that a Linux firmware built from source code isn’t very convenient to use and requires a high level of expertise. Moreover, managing a large number of similar embedded devices individually proved inconvenient, as clients wanted a unified interface to control multiple devices.</p>
<p>We created a web interface for basic functions, but we weren’t entirely satisfied with it due to the need to invoke Linux commands directly from the web, which is neither safe nor reactive.</p>
<p>Therefore, in 2025, we decided to transform the project into Napi-X. This combines NapiOS, with all the advantages of Linux for embedded systems, with a modern API-based management approach and a WebApp built on the Vue framework for intuitive visual control of the system and its applications.</p>
<p>Our closest reference point is OpenWRT, but we acknowledge its limitations as a full-fledged Linux system for routers. It lacks support for heavy software, and its web interface, Luci, is outdated and not optimized for mobile devices.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-napi-x">Why Napi-X?<a href="https://napi-x.com/blog/2025/01/09/index#why-napi-x" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Why Napi-X?" title="Direct link to Why Napi-X?">​</a></h2>
<p>Napi-X offers several key advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>NapiOS at its core</strong> remains an open, lightweight Linux system with firmware-like properties for embedded and network devices: dual partitions and a dedicated user data partition.</li>
<li>A <strong>modern reactive web interface</strong> allows users to manage Linux and its applications both from a desktop workstation and a smartphone. For inexperienced users, we remove the fear of Linux, while for advanced users, we retain the standard SSH access and full openness.</li>
<li><strong>Napi-X.Api</strong> enables system management not only via the WebApp but also through third-party integrations.</li>
<li>The <strong>server-side Napi-X.Api</strong> provides centralized management of multiple authorized devices from a single web application.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-dreams">Our Dreams<a href="https://napi-x.com/blog/2025/01/09/index#our-dreams" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Dreams" title="Direct link to Our Dreams">​</a></h2>
<p>We hope you will also appreciate our approach, and that Napi-X will win the hearts of developers and open-source community users.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>